Phone: 415-746-0604 jimmychen.xin@gmail.com

WEBSITE: jimtie.github.io



Hands-on ability to combine user experience studies with programming skills to evaluate system functionality and usability; Proficiency in creating wireframes, storyboards, mockups, and prototypes; Sensitivity to create appealing layouts and visual elements; Solid technical background to facilitate communication with both developers and designers; Good communication skills in teamwork and demonstrating ideas; Passionate and curious about new knowledge. 6+ years professional design experience, been through the full manufacturing process and have learned programming to enhance understanding of software development.

TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE & SKILLS

UI/UX: Axure, Figma, Sketch, Adobe XD, Marvel POP, Lucidchart, Balsamiq

Visual Processing: Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign

Digital Drawing: Sketchbook

Front End Programming: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, React, SCSS **Back End Programming**: Python, NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, Postgresql

Physical Prototyping: Hand Crafting & 3D Printing

CAD modeling: Solidworks, AutoCAD, Rhino, Alias, 3ds-max, Sketchup

Rendering: Keyshot, Vray, Photoview360

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

QFusion Labs, Inc. (Oakland, CA, USA) DESIGN LEAD

May 2017-PRESENT (http://www.cubit.cc)

- Analyzed the market and re-defined the target users from engineers to students from the research result. Formed Cubit as a STEM/ STEAM educational product. It has been sold to more than 13 states over 50 schools in the US, pilot schools in Australia, England and China as well, and also used by NASA for teaching and training purpose. (https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/edu/teach/activity/heat-flow-programming-challenge/)
- Created detailed PRD (Product Requirement Document) for both hardware and software development, including Physical Requirements, Functional Requirements, Performance Requirements, Interface Requirements, Ergonomics Requirements, etc..
- Hosted 10-15 minutes Design team meet ups 2-3 times per week, assigned works to teammates and sync progress
- Conducted brainstorming sessions and designed concepts in line with client's requirements. Tested new projects with school students and collected their feedbacks for improvement and inspiration.
- In charge of Manufacturing in China. Efficiently scheduled time for components purchasing, PCB boards printing, PCB assembly, enclosure injection molding, testing, product assembly, packaging and shipping. Followed up all the process and make sure the whole process done within a month.

Sercle, Inc. (Fremont, CA, USA) UX/UI DESIGNER

May 2015-Apr 2017

- Designed mobile app UX and UI from scratch. The prototype helped the company successfully raised over \$1.2Million seed fund and the total downloads of the App is over 118K.
- Participated in the business execution, used research data to set up business strategy and guide the design.
- Discussed with CEO, product manager and engineer lead to update the flow chart, wireframes and graphics. Applied agile development method, each iteration takes about 1.5-2 month.
- Used Axure for Site Map, user flow and wire frames, Adobe photoshop to create UI and Marvel POP for prototypes. Did AB testing with users, observed, asked questions and made videos for later analysis. Found it's better to design the appointment page for one-hand-use, because they usually check it when working or driving.

Jimmy Chen Résumé, Page 2

Big Timers, Inc. (San Francisco, CA, USA) UX/UI DESIGNER

Jun 2014-Aug 2015

- Improved user-centered App design
- Discussed about the user-flows and site map with team lead
- Created wireframes and prototype for user testing

Shook-Design Studio (Palo Alto, CA, USA)

Oct 2013 - May 2014

INDUSTRIAL DESIGNER

The main projects I participated:

- -Lotus Elise bumper redesign
- -Smart motorcycle design for Zebra Motors, Denmark
- -Salt Flats Racing car design
- -General Motors Concept car Interior UI design
- -Wearable smart device design
- Evaluates design ideas based on factors such as appealing appearance, design-function relationship
- Integrates findings and concepts and sketches design ideas.
- Presents design to clients and discusses need for modification and change.
- Applied knowledge of design software to create eye-catching creative concepts.
 - Ensured that designs meet the specific branding requirements and corporate standards.

 Negotiating/agreeing contracts with manufacturers on production of packaging, budgets, time scales and graphics for advertising.

Samai Foods Co. (Canada, Remote)

Oct 2012-Oct 2013

PACKAGE DESIGNER

- •Designed the packaging method as well as the graphics with Photoshop. The product is selling in Chinese Market.
- •Did research about package materials and compare the manufacturing cost, and quotes from factories. Built relationship with 2 Chinese package manufacturers.

New Era Architecture Design Co (Beijing, China)

Jul 2009-Jun 2010

INTERIOR/ FURNITURE DESIGNER

- Participated projects and brainstormed ideas
- Did CAD modeling work by using Rhino and Sketch Up

EDUCATION

CERTIFICATE, SOFTWARE ENGINEER, 2020

General Assembly, San Francisco, CA, USA

-Mi-TEA (REACT, HTML, SCSS, JavaScript, MongoDB, Express, Node.js, Bootstrap)

https://mi-tea.herokuapp.com (User: jimmychen.xin@gmail.com Password: jimmy000)

-WAYFARER (REACT, HTML, SCSS, JavaScript, MongoDB, Express, Node.js, Bootstrap)

https://wayfarer-sei09t1.herokuapp.com (User: jimmychen.xin@gmail.com Password: jimmy000)

-INFRARED (Python, Django, Postgresql, HTML, Bootstrap)

https://mi-tea.herokuapp.com

-TOYSLIST (HTML, CSS, JavaScript)

https://github.com/jimtie/toyslist

-KING-KONG GAME (HTML, CSS, JavaScript)

https://github.com/jimtie/Project-0-King-Kong

MASTER OF FINE ARTS, INDUSTRIAL DESIGN, 2014

Academy of Art University, San Francisco, CA, USA

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (INDUSTRIAL DESIGN), 2009

Beijing University of Technology, Beijing, China